BABCOCK UNIVERSITY

CURRICULUM VITAE PHONE: +234-8068856195

E-mail: maitanmi@yahoo.com, or maitanmis@babcock.edu.ng

Personal profile:

Name: MAITANMI, Olusola Stephen (Ph.D)

Area of Specialization: Software Engineering (Cyber Physical Systems)

Status/Rank: Lecturer I

Date of First Employment: 1st March, 2005

Current Employer: Babcock University, Ilisan Remo, Ogun State

Current Position: Undergraduate Lecturer

School: Computer Science & Engineering Sciences

Department: Computer Science

State of Origin: Ekiti

Place of Birth: Ipoti Ekiti, Ekiti

Marital Status: Married

Residential Address: No. 47 Awolowo Avenue, Ilisan Remo, Ogun State

Educational History: Institutions Attended, Grades & Dates

| S/N | Cert./Degree | Type | Year | Grade | Institution | |
|-----|--------------|----------------|------|---------|------------------------|--|
| 1. | 3rd Degree | Ph.D Computer | 2015 | Ph.D | Babcock University, | |
| | | Science | | | Ilisan Remo, Ogun | |
| | | | | | State. | |
| 2. | 2nd Degree | M.Sc. Computer | 2012 | 74% | Babcock University, | |
| | | Science | | | Ilisan Remo, Ogun | |
| | | | | | State. | |
| 3. | 1st Degree | PGD Computer | 2009 | 21 | University of | |
| | | Science | | | Agriculture, Abeokuta, | |
| | | | | | Ogun State | |
| 4. | 1st Degree | HND | 2002 | 3.74% | Kaduna Polytechnic | |
| | | | | Upper | | |
| | | | | Credit | | |
| 5. | 1st Degree | OND | 1999 | 3.65% | Kaduna Polytechnic | |
| | | | | Upper | | |
| | | | | Credit | | |
| 6. | O/L | SSCE | 1995 | 5 | Ipoti High School | |
| | | | | Credits | | |

Professional Qualification

| S/N | Name | Date |
|-----|----------------------|------|
| 1. | OCA-Oracle Certified | 2009 |
| | Associate | |

Work History

| | S/N | Location of | Name | From | To | Begin Status | Current |
|---|-----------------|--------------|-------------|------------|----------|---------------------|------------|
| | | work | | | | | Status |
| • | 1L | Ilisan Remo, | Babcock | 1st March, | Date | Laboratory | Lecturer I |
| | г | Ogun State | University | 2005 | (2016) | Technologist | |
| | 2. ^E | Ilisan Remo, | Babcock | 1st Jan. | Feb. 28, | System | System |
| | A | Ogun State | University | 2005 | 2005 | Engineer | Engineer |
| | 3. | Kaduna | Cosoft Nig, | April 1, | Dec. | Senior | Senior |
| | | | Ltd. | 2004 | 28, | Instructor | Instructor |
| | P | | | | 2004 | | |

Courses Lectured- Undergraduate (2012-Date)

- 1. COSC 101 Introduction to Programming Language in C
- 2. COSC 102 Introduction to Programming Language in C
- 3. GEDS 116 Introduction to Computer Science

- 4. COSC 202 Visual Basic.Net
- 5. INSY 401 Website Design & Publishing from 2012 till date
- 6. INSY 402 Internet Technology from 2012 till date

Project Supervision Completed-Undergraduate (2012-Date)

** 15 Students

Areas Of Research Interest

- Cyber Physical Systems
- Web Development
- IT Security

Academic Publications

Foreign Papers (Journals)

- 1. **Stephen O. Maitanmi, Sunday A. Idowu , Olawale J. Omotosho, Olusegun A. Ojesanmi (2015)** Cyber Physical Systems: Error Verification and Prediction in Smart Medical Devices. IOSR Journal of Computer Engineering (IOSR-JCE (Sep. Oct. 2015), PP 63-73
- 2. Sunday Anuoluwa Idowu, Olawale Jacob Omotosho, Olusegun Ayodeji Ojesanmi, Stephen Olusola Maitanmi.(2015) Cyber-Physical Systems: A Framework for Prediction of Error in Smart Medical Devices. American Journal of Software Engineering and Applications 2015; 4(4): 71-79
- 3. **Idowu, S. A, Maitanmi S. O Transactions (2014)** Distributed Database Systems: Issues and Challenges. International Journal of Advances in Computer Science and Communication Engineering (IJACSCE) Vol 2 Issue I (March2014) Pg. 24-26
- 4. Adekola Olubukola D, Awodele Oludele, Maitanmi Olusola (2014) Model-based Course Design for effective Blended Learning Approaches Volume 4, Issue 1, January 2014 ISSN: 2277 128X International Journal of Advanced Research in Computer Science and Software Engineering
- 5. **Maitanmi S. O, Adekunle, Y. A and Agbaje M. O (2013)** Model-Based Cellular Automata on spread of Rumours. *International journal of computer & Organization Trends (IJCOT)*
- 6. Adekola Daniel Bukola, Maitanmi, Olusola Stephen and Adio Adesina Kamorudeen (2013) ETHICAL USE OF COMPUTER TECHNOLOGY. Scholars Journal of Engineering & Technology (SJET)Sch. J.Eng. Tech., 2013; 1(4):247-250 ISSN 2321-

- 7. **Ogunlere Samson, Maitanmi Olusola and Gregory Nwodi (2013)** Design and Implementation of Intelligence Car Parking Systems. *International Journal of Computer Science & Business Informatic, ISSN: 1694-2108 Vol. 6,1-16 N0.1 October*, 2013
- 8. Maitanmi Olusola S., Okolie, S. O and Adio Adesina K. (2013) Queue Management Systems for Congestion Control: Case study of First Bank, Nigeria. *International Journal of Advanced Studies in Computer Science & Engineering, Vol. 2, Issue 5, 2013 Pg.54-58*
- 9. Maitanmi Olusola Stephen, Ogunlere Samson Ojo, Adekunle Yinka, Gregory Onwodi and Malasowe Bridget (2013) Design and Implementation of a Real-Time Vehicle Tracking System. *International Journal of Research in Commerce, IT & Managemen, Vol.,No.3(2013), Issue No. 09 Pg. 86-92 (September)*
- 10. Ogbonna Chibueze, Maitanmi Olusola, Awodele Oludele and Akintunde Adedayo (2013) Delivering E-learning in Project Management: Determining Participants' Infrastructure Priorities and Contaminates. *International Journal of Computer (IJC)Vol. 9 NO 1Pg. 18-23*
- 11. Maitanmi, Olusola, Adekunle Yinka Malasowe Bridget, and Gregory Nwodi (2013) Information Technology as a vehicle to Millennium Development. *International Journal of Advanced Studies in Computer Science & Engineering, Vol. 2. Issue 4,Pg. 31-38. 2013*
- 12. Maitanmi, Olusola, Adekunle Yinka, Adio Adesina Kamorudeen, Gregory Nwodi and Malasowe Bridget (2013) Model- Based Information Retrieval System. *International Journal of Computer (IJC) Vol. 10, NO1 Pg 8-17*
- 13. Maitanmi, Olusola, Malasowe Bridget, Emuobonuvie Erhinyoja Andy, Adekunle Yinka and Gregory Nwodi (2013) Neural Network Models: A Basic Statistical Tool for Data analysis and Forecasting. *International Journal of Computer (IJC)Vol. 8 No. 1. Pg1-7*
- 14. Adekunle Yinka, Bisong Ekaba Ononse, Fagbemi Oluwabanke, Obuke Enifome, Alao Jimi, and Maitanmi, Olusola (2013) Framework Model for a Soil Suitability Decision Support System for Crop Production in Nigeria. *American Journal of Engineering Research (AJER) Vol. 02, Issue-06, Pg.-09-13*
- 15. Omotunde Ayokunle, Maitanmi, Olusola Stephen, Alao Olujimi, Ogunlere Samson Ojo, Soyege Seyi (2013) Wireless Heterogeneous Network. *International Journal of Computer (IJC)Vol. 7, NO 1 Pg. 1-10*
- 16. **Maitanmi, S. O, Ogunlere, S. O, Ayinde Semiu, and Adekunle Y. (2013)** Cyber Crimes and Cyber laws in Nigeria. *The International Journal of Engineering and Science (THE IJES) Vol. 2, Issue 4 Pg. 19-25, 2013*
- 17. Maitanmi, S. O, Ogunlere, S. O, Ayinde Semiu, and Adekunle Y. (2013) Impact of Cyber Crimes On Nigerian Economy. The International Journal of Engineering and

- 18. Maitanmi Olusola Stephen, Adio Adesina Kamorudeen, Adekunle Yinka and Gregory Onwodi (2013) Open, Flexible and Distributed Learning Environment. *International Journal of Computer (IJC). Vol. 1, NO 1. Pg 7-16.*
- 19. **Maitanmi, S. O, Ayinde, S. A, Adekola, O. D, Omotunde, A. O, Malasowe, B. O (2013)** Web-Based Family Building. *International Journal of Advances in Computer Science and Technology. Vol 2, No.6, June, 2013*
- 20. **Maitanmi S. O, Awodele O. Ogbonna C. and Osundina S. (2013)** Cashless Society: Drive's and challenges in Nigeria. *International Journal of Information Sciences and Techniques (IJIST) Vol.3, No.2, March 2013.*
- 21. **Malasowe Bridget, Awodele Oludele, Maitanmi Olusola, Emuobonuvie Andy (2013)**A Survey Of DNA Computing Quest Journals Journal of Research in Humanities and Social Science Volume1 ~ Issue 4 (2013) pp: 25-33 ISSN(Online) :2321-9467
- 22. **Maitanmi, S. O, Idowu, S. A (2013)** Evaluation of Content Management Systems Performance. (IOSR) Journal of Computer Engineering (IOSR-JCE) Vol. 9, Issue 4 (Mar-Apr. 2013), Pg. 62-69
- 23. Adekunle, Y. A , Maitanmi, S.O, Malasowe, B.O, and Osundina, S.A (2012) Economics of Cloud Computing. *International Journal of Engineering and Innovative (IJEIT). Vol. 1, Issue 4, April, 2013*
- 25. **Maitanmi, S.O and Adekunla, Y.A (2011)** Selected Problems on Mobile Agent Communication. *International Journal of Computer Science and Information Security (IJCSIS) Vol. 9, No. 6, June, 2011, 235-239*

Nigerian Journal

26. **Agbaje, M.Olugbenga, Awodele, Oludele, Joshua, J.Vincent, Maitanmi, O. Stephen, Okolie S.O (2012)** A Trustworthy SMS Based Voting System Architecture. *National Journal of Nigeria Computer Society. Vol. 19 No.1, June, 2012*

Chapters in Books

- Adekunle Y. A, Adio A. K, Efuwape B. T, Maitanmi S. O, Okunlola J. T and Toyinbo R. O (2013) Basic University Statistics. Oyo State Government Printing Press, Ibadan. (ISBN: 978-978-942-003-2).
- 28. Maitanmi, S.0, Awodele, O., Okolie S.O, Ogunlere S.O, Omotosho, J.O et al (2010) "General Introduction to Computing' by Computer Science & Mathematics, Babcock University. (ISBN:978-37476-3-4)

Thesis/Projects (Personal) Completed (1996 – 2015)

- Maitanmi, S. O (2015) Cyber Physical Systems: A Model for Verification and Error Prediction in Smart Medical Devices - Ph.D Thesis Computer Science (Software Engineering), Babcock University, Ilisan Rem,o, Ogun State, Nigeria
- Maitanmi, S. O (2012) Evaluation of Content Management Systems Performance- M.Sc
 Project, Babcock University, Ilisan Rem,o, Ogun State, Nigeria
- iii. Maitanmi, S. O (2008) Selected Problems on Mobile Agent Communication- PGDProject, University of Agriculture, Abeokuta, Ogun State, Nigeria
- iv. Maitanmi, S. O (2002) Customer Control Systems HND Project, Kaduna Polytechnic, Kaduna
- v. Maitanmi S. O (1999) Computerised Teaching Aids Software –OND Project, Kaduna Polytechnic, Kaduna

Conferences Attended (2012 - date)

- 1. Nigeria Computer Society (NCS) 26th National Conference & Exhibition. Theme: Information Technology for National Safety & Security, July 19 to July 21, 2016, NAF Conference Center, Abuja, Nigeria.
- 2. 2nd Distinguished Lecture and Stakeholders' Forum on E-learning, University of Ibadan Distance Learning Center. 6-7 August, 2015
- 3. Computer Professionals (Registration Council of Nigeria) Information Technology Professional's Assembly 2015. Theme: Developments in Information Technology in Nigeria: The Gains, Challenges and Way forward. Date: 10-11 June, 2015 at Transcorp Hotel, Calabar, Cross River State.
- 4. International Conferences on Science, Technology, Education, Arts, Management & Social Sciences (isteams) held at Unilorin, March 11-13, 2015
- 5. CES Instructors Training Workshop held at Babcock University, March 2014
- 6. Computer Professional of Nigeria Executive Training Workshop held at Abeokuta 24-28 Feb., 2014
- 7. E-learning online training workshop in Netherland, August-December 2011
- 8. Driving Business, Efficiency & Expansion organized by Oracle held at Silver bird Galleria Ikoyi lagos 4/11/2008

Conferences Attended with Papers Presentations (2012 – date)

1. **Maitanmi, S. O & Malasowe Bridget.** (2015) Imperatives for the Establishment of National Database to Address Security Issues in Nigeria. International Conferences on Science, Technology, Education, Arts, Management & Social Sciences (isteams) held at Unilorin, March 11-13, 2015

2. Sunday Idowu and Maitanmi Sola

WEB Applications and Services Security: On Preventing Language – Based Attacks. 9th International Conference on Cyber Warfare and Security. Purdue University West Lafayette, Indiana, USA 24-25 March, 2014.

- 3. **Maitanmi, S. O and Idowu S. A (2014)** Embedded Systems in Healthcare Systems by in 1st International Conference on Advanced Computerised Systems & Emerging Technologies. November 30- December 3, 2014
- 4. **Maitanmi, S. O (2011)** Paper Presentation in Ibadan Polytechnic in a National Conference organized by the Faulty of Environmental Studies (FES) tilted 'Millennium Development Goals: Challenges for sustainable Development in Nigeria. Subtitled 'Information Communication Technology, A drive for Millennium Development Goals' March 9-11, 2011.

Membership of Professional bodies

- Member of Computer Professional of Nigeria (MCPN)
- Member of Nigeria Computer Society (NCS)
- Member of Association of Computer Machinery (MACM)

Contributions to Community Development

- 1. Babcock University Platform Committee Member 2013-Date
- 2. Seventh -Day Adventist Church Serving Deacon, Ile-Ife, Osun State, Niegria
- 3. Organised a seminar for all Babcock University Secretaries in October 13-14, 2009 on a course titled 'Computer Risk, Management & Control'
- 4. GEDS 116 Coordinator for Computer Science Department from 2012-Date.
- 5. E-learning coordinator for Computer Science Department

- 6. Completed Module 1, 2 and 3 of Institution of Faith and Learning
- 7. Member of Caleb's University Strategic Plan (2016-2010) Retreat, held at Babcock University, Guest House Between 13-16, March, 2016.

Editorial Engagement

- 1. International Journal of Computer Science and Business Informatics httl://ijcsbi.org/index.php/ijcsbi
- 2. American Journal of Software Engineering & Applications http://www.sciencepublishinggroup.com/

Career Plan and Progression

- **a. Immediate Career Goal:** To participate in foreign trainings, seminars and conferences for self-development in my career.
- **b. Mid-term Career Goal:** To concentrate in research, article publications in reputable foreign journals and books. This is in addition to classroom regular quality teaching to my students.
- **c.** Long term Career Goal: To make the best of my career in academics at the highest level in the area of quality research.

Extra-Curricula Activities

- Playing Table-tennis
- Reading
- Farming

Referees:

i. Prof. S. A Idowu Ph.D

Professor of Computer Science, Computer science Department, Babcock University, Ilisan Remo, Ogun State. P. M. B. 21244, Ikeja, Lagos.

E-mail:saidowu@gmail.com 07038022071

ii. Prof O. J. Omotosho Ph.D

Professor of Instrumentation, Computer science Department, Babcock University, Ilisan Remo, Ogun State. P. M. B. 21244, Ikeja, Lagos.

E-mail: ojomotosho1@yahoo.com 08034951089

iii. Dr. A. Akinsanya Ph.D

Senior Lecture, Computer Science Department, Babcock University, Ilisan Remo, Ogun State, Nigeria. Agriculture, Ogun State.

E-mail: adebola_akinsanya@yahoo.com 08065967348